A Guide to the Papers of James Monroe 1778-1831
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- James Monroe to Capt. A. Partridge 1827 August 9, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
  #3184
- James Monroe to J[ohn] H[artwell] Cocke1827 August 9, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
  #1480
- James Monroe to Charles Fenton Mercer 1827 October 17, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; docketed; Barrow. (Box 2)
  #5914
- James Monroe to Dr. James Walker 1827 November 17, ALS, 1 p.; Barrow. (Box 2)
- James Madison to James Monroe 1828 February 5, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; docketed. Photocopy. Original in James Madison pape Tracy W. McGregor Library. (Box 2)
  #2832
- James Monroe to Charles Fenton Mercer 1828 March 24, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
  #9210-f
- James Monroe to [unidentified recipient] 1828 December 10, ALS, 1 p.; docketed; Barrow. (Box 2)
- James Monroe to Dr. James Wallace 1828 December 15, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; docketed; Barrow. Tracy W. McGregor Library (Box 2)
  #2318
- James Monroe to John H. Cocke 1829 January 8, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- James Monroe to "Dear Sir" 1829 February 11, ALS, 1 p.; docketed; photocopy. Original in Johns Hopkins University Library? (Box 2)
  #9156
- James Monroe to John Bayly 1829 April 6, ALS, 1 p.; transcript included. (Box 2)
- James Monroe to [François de Barbé-Marbois] 1829 June 24, ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
  #4776-a
- James Monroe to Egbert Reed Watson 1829 August 20, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed; silked. (Box 2)
  #38-596
- James Monroe to [Professor Robley Dunglison?] 1829 September 5, ALS, 1 p.; docketed; transcript included. (Box 2)
  #10827
- James Monroe to Mr. Agg 1829 November 3, ALS, 1 p. Tracy W. McGregor Library (Box 2)
- James Monroe to Literary Fund 1829 November 30, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; Barrow. (Box 2)
  #3351
- James Monroe to [Dr. James W. Wallace] 1830 January 26, ALS, 1 p. (Box 2)
  #6077
- James Monroe to Peter S. Du Ponuau 1830 February 8, ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; docketed. (Box 2)
- James Monroe to Egbert Reed 1830 June 6, ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed; silked. (Box 2)
- James Monroe to Egbert Reed 1830 July 5, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed; silked. (Box 2)
- James Monroe to John S. Skinner 1830 November 18, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. with address leaf; docketed; Barrow. (Box 2)
- James Monroe to Egbert Reed 1830 January 30, ALS, 1 p.; silked. (Box 2)
- James Monroe to [unidentified recipient] 1831 March 19, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box 2)
- James Monroe to John H. Cocke, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 2)
- James Monroe: Fragment of manuscript on the acquisition of Florida n.d., AMS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box 2)
  #6435
- James Monroe - Notes on the Constitution n.d., AM, 1 p., transcript included. (Box 2)
- James Monroe to Dr. Everett n.d., ALS, 1 p. with address leaf; docketed; damaged; Barrow. (Box 2)
- Notes in the hand of James Monroe concerning education removed from La Science du Governement, formerly part of Monroe's library n.d., AD, 2 p. on 2 l., includes fragments of text on rear of both documents (Box 2)
  #6278
- John Mercer to James Monroe, 1814 Feb. 23
  #3525-y
- John Holmes to James Monroe, 1816 June 2
  #14816